

# Michael Ziegler



4839 43rd Avenue Kenosha, WI 53144



Mobile(US): +1(815) 321-2752



Mikeziegler123@gmail.com

### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

As a software developer and college graduate in 2019, I am excited to be at the deployment phase of my new career. I have held responsible roles in a variety of professional fields, and my unique variety of industry often leads me toward creative solutions to complex development problems.

- ★ Graduated from Middle Tennessee State University on May 4th, 2019.
- **★** Studied Law and Computer Science.
- **★** Natural problem solver with strong analytical and interpersonal skills.
- ★ 4+ years programming/development skills.

Knowledgeable & Pursuant in Learning: Best programming practices, effective practical algorithms, hands-on data structure(s) application, scalability, embedded systems, Linear Regression,

### **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

C++ [Visual Studio 2019, Codeblocks, CodeLite]

**OBJ-C** [LeetCode, Visual Studio 2019] JAVA [ Dr. Java, Eclipse Studio, "JavaFX"]

[ M-SQLExpress, SQL Management Studio 18 ] **★** SQL

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

### The City Of Lake Forest, — IT Internship Lake Forest, IL | Lake Forest Municipal Center

January 2020 - PRESENT

Phone: (847) 810-3591

- Supported the IT Division in the general maintenance of hardware and software.
- Administered user moves, adds, and changes in The City's Active Directory environment and associated
- Imaged and deployed new workstations, laptops, and tablets.

### Rogers Enterprise, Inc. — Certified Consultant Racine, WI | Regency Mall

August 2019 - January 2020 Phone: (262) 598-0500

- Recruited, interviewed and trained new staff during management transition.
- Designed and implemented freelance IT solutions to resolve technical challenges during OS transition.

### **EDUCATION**

Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro TN B.S. Pre-Law Cognate/Computer Science | GPA: 3.0 August 2016 - May 4th, 2019 | Full Time / Transfered Credits

# Murfreesboro, TN | City Courthouse | Judges Office

**EDUCATIONAL INTERNSHIPS | CONTRIBUTIONS** 

- Positioned for legal experience, remembered for technological help and knowledge.
- Offered to run social media campaign for the next election cycle.

# Pre-Law Internship: Senator Pamela J Althoff Crystal Lake, IL | Senator's Office

Pre-Law Internship: Judge McFarlin | Tidwell

Constituent Data entry during an active election cycle; Parade Planning.

## **Curriculum & Academic Policy Council Member** Crystal Lake, IL | McHenry County College

- Student Representative
- Nominated Board position

### McHenry County College Student Senator Crystal Lake, IL | McHenry County College

- Active within student government: 2009-2013
- Student body elected position

### **PROJECTS**

### **Smart Home Synergy** — *Startup*

Developed compatibility matrix for smart home devices similar to model used by 'PCPartsPicker.com'.





